Register of the Allan E. Goodman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1975 INCREMENT, 1956-1974 (Boxes 38-108)
  - SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1974 (Boxes 52-96)
    - U.S.
      - Foreign policy in Vietnam
        - Denton, Frank, "A Vietnam Alternative,", 1968
        - Gelb, Leslie H.
          - "U.S. Policy and Vietnam: Lessons Learned," Chapter 1, "The Roosevelt Administration, 1940-1942,", 1970
          - "Vietnam: The System Worked,", 1970
        - Hoffmann, Stanley, "Vietnam and American Foreign Policy,", 1968
        - Katz, Amrom H., "The Short Run and the Long Walk,", 1966
        - Leites, Nathan, "Edwin Reischauer and the Choice on the War,", 1967
        - McManaway, Clayton, "A New Departure in U.S. Policy toward Indochina: A Proposal,", 1971
        - Reinhardt, G. C., "America's Crossroads: Vietnam,", 1967
        - Scott, Douglas, "America in Vietnam: A Personal View,", 1968 (Box 81)
      - Immigration
      - Intellectuals
      - Legal aid to the poor
      - Military aid
      - Military aid to South Vietnam
      - Military intelligence
      - Military interventions
        - General
        - Thomson, James C., Jr., "The Effect of Our Involvement in Vietnam on Future U.S. Patterns of Intervention," with comment by Edwin Reischauer, 1968
      - Mutual security treaties
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Fontera, Richard M., "Change Agents: India and the United States,", 1969
        - Montgomery, John D., "Transferability of What?,", 1969
      - National Security Council
      - Political campaign reform
      - Politics
      - Relations with Cambodia
      - Relations with China
        - General
        - Rusk, Dean, "United States Policy toward Communist China,", 1966
      - Relations with Greece
      - Relations with Indonesia
      - Relations with Japan
        - General
        - U.S. Department of State, "The United States and Japan: Prime Minister Tanaka's Washington Visit, July 31-August 1, 1973, and the Tokyo Meeting of the Joint U.S.-Japan Committee on Trade and Economic Affairs, July 16-17, 1973,"
        - Wolf, Charles, Jr., "Japan-U.S. Relations and Asian Development Problems,", 1968
      - Relations with Latin America. Smith, Walton N., "Summary of Latin American Reactions to United States Military Assistance,", undated
      - Relations with South Korea
      - Relations with South Vietnam
        - General
        - Pohle, Victoria S., "The Limited Influence of the U.S. on Vietnam's Economic Affairs,", 1966
      - Relations with Thailand
        - General
        - Bundy, William P., Meet the Press interview, NBC, 1966 September 4
        - Martin, Ambassador Graham, speech to the American Chamber of Commerce, Bangkok, 1967 January 18
        - U.S. Departments of State and Commerce, "U.S. Trade and Investment Program for Thailand: Fiscal Year 1971,", 1970
      - Relations with the Philippines
      - Relations with the U.S.S.R.
      - Secrecy in government
      - Universities
        - General
        - Murphey, John, "Publish or Perish: Some Thoughts on University Evaluation of Its Faculty,", undated
      - Vice Presidency
      - Volunteer army
      - Volunteers in Service to America (Box 82)
        - General
        - Mims, George L. and Glen T. Nygreen, "The AID/IIE/VISTA 1967 Summer Associates Program: A Report on the VISTA Summer Associates Program for Foreign Students,"
        - Sey, Omar, "Report on VISTA-AID-IIE Foreign Student Volunteer Program,", 1967
    - U.S.S. Pueblo incident
    - U.S.S.R.
      - General
      - Defense policy
        - General
        - Hunter, Douglas, "The Soviet Threat to U.S. Deterrence Forces and U.S. Defensive Options to Maintain Deterrence,", undated
        - Lambeth, Benjamin S., "The Sources of Soviet Military Doctrine,", 1972
        - Polmar, Norman, "Soviet Naval Power: Challenge for the 1970s,", 1972
        - "Threat Perception and the Soviet National Security Community: The Case Studies Approach,", undated
        - Warner, Edward L., III, "Soviet Force Posture,", undated
        - Wolfe, Thomas W., "Evolution of Soviet Military Policy,", 1968
      - Foreign policy
      - Foreign policy in the Middle East
        - General
        - Golan, Galia, "The Soviet Involvement in the Middle East,", 1971
      - Internal dissension
      - National development planning
      - Politics
      - Press
      - Relations with China
      - Relations with India
      - Relations with Latin America
      - Relations with North Vietnam
    - Urban development planning
      - General. Hearle, Edward F. R., "Information Systems for City Management,", 1963
      - Korea, South
        - General
        - Berkman, Herman G., "Report on Planning Consultation, March 12, 1970-June 23, 1970,", undated
        - Fortune, Mark, "Mobilizing for Urbanization: Republic of Korea,", 1971
    - Urbanization (Box 83)
      - General
        - General
        - Frolic, B. M., "Noncomparative Communism: Chinese and Soviet Cities,", 1971
        - "The Influence of Urbanization on Personal Interaction: A Brief Survey of Classical Thought,", undated
        - Urban Development Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, July 7-8, 1971
        - Urban Development Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1971 October 13-14
      - Asia
      - Bibliography
        - General
        - "Assimilation of Rural Migrants in Cities,", 1971
      - Cambodia
      - France
      - Germany
      - Ghana
      - Great Britain
      - India
      - Indonesia
        - General
        - Indonesia Institute of Technology Center for Regional and Planning Studies, "Pilot Research Project on Middle Cities' Services in Indonesia, 1971,"
      - Kenya
      - Korea, South, Cho, Lee-Jay, "Demographic Aspects of Urbanization in Korea,", 1973
      - Latin America
      - Malaysia
      - Nigeria
      - Social science research
        - General
        - Shindler, Attlee E., "Urbanizing the University: A Preliminary Report of a Survey of Urban Studies Programs,", 1969 (Box 84)
        - Questionnaire forms
      - Southeast Asia
        - General
        - Ad Hoc Urban Development Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, University of California, Berkeley, 1972 August 7-9
        - "Interdisciplinary Perspectives on Policy for the Future of the Southeast Asian City," proposed seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, 1972-1973
        - Laquian, Aprodicio A., "Urban Tensions in Southeast Asia in the 70's,", 1971
        - "Social Science Research for Urban Development in Southeast Asia," Southeast Asian Social Science Association Conference, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, 1972 December 18-23
      - Statistics
      - Thailand
      - U.S.
        - General
        - Pickard, Jerome P., "U.S. Metropolitan Growth and Expansion, 1970-2000, with Population Projections,", undated
      - Vietnam, South
      - Zambia
    - Urbanization and law
      - General
      - "Housing and Legal Institutions in the Developing Countries: Some Questions and Suggestions,", 1971
      - Mandelker, Daniel R., "The Capacity of the Legal System to Facilitate the Urban Development Process: Korea and the Philippines,", undated
    - Urbanization and political behavior
      - General
      - Africa. Hayward, Fred M., "Political Participation, Impact of Development and National Integration: Some Observations Drawn from the African Context,", 1970
      - Chile
      - Colombia. Harvin, Eugene, "The Power Structure in a Shantytown,", 1970
      - Ghana
      - India
      - Korea, South
      - Latin America
      - Malaysia
      - Mexico
        - General
        - Cornelius, Wayne, "The Study of Political Leadership in Mexican Squatter Settlements: Urban Caciquismo,", 1971
      - Philippines, Laquian, Aprodicio A., "The Political Integration of Urban Squatters and Slum Dwellers in the Philippines,", undated
      - U.S.
      - Venezuela
    - Urbanization and power structures
    - Urbanization and the environment
    - Venezuela, Insurgency (Box 85)
    - Vien, General Cao Van
    - Viet Cong
      - General
        - General
        - "Nature of South Vietnam's Liberation Army,", 1963
      - History, "Experiences of the South Vietnam Revolutionary Movement during the Past Several Years,", 1963
      - Organization
      - Tactics
        - Betts, Russell H., "Viet Cong Village Control: Some Observations on the Origin and Dynamics of Modern Revolutionary War,", 1969
        - Pike, Douglas, "The Viet-Cong Strategy of Terror,", 1970
        - "Resolution Issued by the 9th Conference of COSVN,", 1969
    - Vietnam
      - Bibliography
      - Colonial period
      - Communism, Viet-Nam Documents and Research Notes
        Includes numbers 1-7, 10-19, 21-27, 41, 43-44, 46-49, 54, 56-59, 63, 65-66, 68-69, 73, 81, 89, and 95-96.
      - Communism, Viet-Nam Documents and Research Notes (Box 86)
        Includes an index as well as numbers 97 and 99-109.
      - Geneva settlement, 1954
      - Nationalism, Lam, Truong Buu, "Vietnamese Nationalism from 1900 to 1918,", 1966
      - Unification
        - General
        - Hien, Nguyen Van, "Significance of the Partition of Vietnam and Its Unification Prospect,", 1971
    - Vietnam, North (Box 87)
      - Defense policy
      - Foreign policy
        - Gurtov, Melvin, "Indochina in North Vietnamese Strategy,", 1971
        - Kellen, Konrad, "1971 and Beyond: The View from Hanoi,"
      - Politics
        - General
        - Turley, William S., "The DRV since the Death of Ho Chi Minh: The Politics of a Revolution in Transition,", 1971
      - Relations with Cambodia, Brown, David E., "Exporting Insurgency: The Communists in Cambodia,", undated
      - Relations with Thailand
    - Vietnam, South
      - General
      - Agrovilles
      - Buddhists
      - Cabinet ministers (Box 88)
        - General
        - Wurfel, David, "Backgrounds of South Vietnamese Cabinets,", undated
      - Catholics
      - Constitutions
        - General
        - 1956
        - 1967
      - Corruption
      - Coup, November 1963
      - Culture
      - Diem (Ngo Dinh) regime
      - Economy
        - General
        - Heymann, H., Jr., "Imposing Communism on the Economy of South Vietnam: A Conjectural View,", undated
        - Smithies, Arthur, "Economic Development in Vietnam: The Need for External Resources,", undated
      - Education
      - Elections
        - General
          - General
          - Ehrlich, Richard, "Village and Hamlet Elections as a Means of Political Socialization,", 1971
          - Pool, Ithiel de Sola, "A Note about Elections in South Viet Nam,", 1971
          - Tull, Theresa A., "Broadening the Base: South Vietnamese Elections, 1967-1971,"
        - Legislative, 1956, 1959, 1966
        - 1967 (Box 89)
          - General
          - Harrison, James Q., "Elections Revolution: An Analysis of the Fall Elections in Vietnam,", undated
          - Penniman, Howard R., "Decision in South Vietnam,", 1967
          - Wurfel, David, "Dr. David Wurfel Reports on Vietnam,", 1967
          - Legislative
            - General
            - Lower House
            - Upper House
          - Presidential
            - General
            - "The Republic of Vietnam's Presidential Election, September 3, 1967,", undated
        - 1970
          - Legislative, Upper House
          - Local
        - 1971 (Box 90)
          - General
          - Legislative, Lower House
          - Presidential
            - General
            - Kirk, Donald, "The Thieu Presidential Campaign: Background and Consequences of the Single-Candidacy Phenomenon,", 1971
        - Social science research
      - Government
      - Justice
        - Chau, Hoi Tri, "A Way of Reforming the Bar Association,", 1967
        - Hung, Nguyen Quoc, "The Ministry of Justice and the Present Judicial System,", 1968
      - Land reform
      - Laws
      - Legislative-executive relations
      - Legislature
        - General
        - Apportionment
        - Debates
        - Internal organization
        - Legislators (Box 91)
          - Biographic data
          - Tabulation of characteristics
        - Lower House
          - General
          - Agendas
          - Blocs
          - Committees
          - Independence Parliamentary Bloc
          - Internal organization
          - Legislation
          - Legislators
            - General
            - Absenteeism
            - Tabulation of characteristics
          - Petitions
          - Responsiveness to constituents (Box 92)
        - Rules
        - Upper House
          - General
          - Legislators
            - Biographic data
            - Tabulation of characteristics
      - Local government
        - General
        - Allen, Luther A. and Pham Ngoc An, "A Vietnamese District Chief in Action,", 1963
        - Donoghue, John D.
          - "Cam An: A Fishing Village in Central Vietnam,", undated
          - "My Thuan: A Mekong Delta Village in South Vietnam,", 1963
        - Giau, Truong Ngoc and Lloyd W. Woodruff, "The Delta Village of My Thuan: Some Administrative and Financial Aspects,", undated
        - Michigan State University Vietnam Advisory Group, "Cases in Vietnamese Administration,", undated
        - Woodruff, Lloyd W., "Local Administration in Vietnam: The Number of Local Units,", 1963
        - Zasloff, Joseph J., "A Study of Administration in Binh Minh District,", undated
      - Maps
      - Minorities
      - National development planning
        - General
        - "Administrative and Political Reform in Vietnam," Development Administration Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1968 March 13-14
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Boston, 1969 March 28-29
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1967 December 6
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1968 November 1
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1970 February 13
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1968 April 3
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1969 January 30
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1969 October 20-21
        - Development Administration Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, San Francisco, 1969 December 5-6
        - Plenary Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1967 October 6-7 (Box 93)
        - U.S. Senate Staff Foreign Policy Seminars, Washington, D.C., 1969
          - General
          - Reynolds, Dana D.
            - "Building Political Bases for Vietnam and Asian Development"
            - "Key Issues in South Vietnam's Post-War Development and Stability"
        - "Viet-Nam: The Problems of Development under Conditions of Insurgency," Vietnam Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1967 February 4
        - Young, Kenneth T., "Regionalism and Vietnam,", undated
      - National Reconciliation Policy
      - Nationalism, "Vietnamese National Identity: Constants and Change," Asia Society and Council on Vietnamese Studies Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, 1968 October 9
      - Pacification
      - Political community
      - Political elite
      - Political prisoners
      - Politics
        - General
        - Hy, Nguyen Tien, "On Political Opposition,", 1960
        - MIT/Harvard Joint Faculty Seminar on Political Development, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1967 October 4
        - "Political Development in South Vietnam," Council on Vietnamese Studies Conference, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Racine, Wisconsin, 1967 May 14-15
        - Pond, Elizabeth, "Vietnamese Politics: Longer Term,", 1969
      - Provinces
        - Sadec Province, Smith, Blake W. H., "Sadec Provincial Profile,", 1968
        - Statistics
      - Radio broadcasting, Advanced Research Projects Agency, "The Extent of Radio Listening,", undated
      - Refugees, Human Sciences Research, Inc., Refugee Study Project
        - "Preliminary Data on the Refugee Population of Cam Lo Government Resettlement Camp, Quang Tri Province,", 1967
        - "Preliminary Data on the Refugee Population of Ngoc Thanh Government Resettlement Camp, Quang Nam Province,", 1967
        - "Preliminary Data on the Refugee Population of Quang Tri (City) Resettlement Area, Quang Tri Province,", 1967
      - Rural development (Box 94)
        - General
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1970 April 24-25
        - Council on Vietnamese Studies Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1969 June 2-3
        - Nguyen Cong Tru (Local Village Development) Program
          - General
          - Ferguson, Ben R. and Edgar Owens, "Revolutionary Development in South Vietnam: The Next Step,", 1967
          - "Local Village Development Program,", undated
        - Research proposals
      - Social science research
        - General
        - "Reconstruction: Further Development in South Viet-Nam: A Role for the U.S. Academic Community,", 1967
        - Researchers
      - Supreme Court
    - Vietnam Studies Coordinating Group
    - Vietnam War
      - Cambodia
        - General
        - Incursion, 1970 May
      - Cease-fire, "Political and Economic Implications of the Cease-Fire in Vietnam," 12th working session, Centre d'Etude du Sud-Est Asiatique et de l'Extreme-Orient, Brussels, 1973 May 15-16
      - Civilian casualties
      - Computer simulations (Box 95)
        - General
        - Werbos, Paul, "Mathematics and Vietnam: The Vietnam Computer Simulation and Its Future,", 1968
      - Contingency plans
        - Gurtov, Melvin, "Forced Withdrawal from Vietnam and U.S. Alternatives,", 1966
        - Horelick, Arnold L., " 'Sour' Contingencies and U.S. Policy in Vietnam,", 1966
        - Robinson, Thomas W., "On Dealing with Possible Political Changes in Vietnam Harmful to American Policy,", 1966
      - Cost, Barro, S. M., "On Counting the Cost of Vietnam,", 1967
      - Counterinsurgency
        - Farmer, James, "Counterinsurgency: Principles and Practices in Viet-Nam,", 1964
        - Gastil, Raymond D.
          - "Counterinsurgency and South Vietnam: Some Alternatives,", 1967
          - "Toward the Development of a More Acceptable Set of Limits for Counterinsurgency,", 1967
        - Shubert, G. H., "Research on Counterinsurgency and Vietnam,", 1968
      - Credibility gap
      - Developments in 1970
      - Developments in 1972
      - Effects on U.S. society
      - Laos
        - General
        - Langer, Paul F., "Laos: Search for Peace in the Midst of War,", 1967
      - Opinion
        - France
        - International
        - U.S.
      - Origins
      - Peace proposals
        - General
        - Joint Meeting of Council on Vietnamese Studies and and Political Development Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Washington, D.C., 1969 May 3
        - "Negotiation Attempts on Viet-Nam,", undated
        - Pauker, Ewa T., ed., "A Discussion Concerning a Negotiated Termination of the Vietnam Conflict,", 1967
        - Pike, Douglas, "The Possible Role of Elections in a Political Settlement with the NLF,", 1971
        - Thai, Vu Van, "A Settlement of the Vietnam Conflict in the Context of S. E. Asia,", 1967
      - Tactics
        - Carter, G. A. and M. B. Shaffer, "On Some Counter-productive Aspects of Tactical Force Employment in South Vietnam: Interviews with Vietnamese Prisoners and Civilians,", 1967
        - West, Bing, "Pursuit,", 1968
        - West, F. J., Jr.
          - "Area Security: The Need, the Composition, and the Components,", 1968
          - "The Combined Action Platoon,", 1968 (Box 96)
          - "The Enclave,", 1968
          - "The Strike Teams,", 1968
          - "The Strike Teams: Tactical Performance and Strategic Potential,", 1969
      - U.S. bombing campaign
      - U.S. prisoners of war
      - U.S. strategy
        - General
          - Eccles, Rear Admiral Henry E., "The Viet Nam Hurricane, or the Pentagon in the Eye of the Storm,", 1969
          - Ellsberg, Daniel, "Some Prospects and Problems in Vietnam,", 1968
          - Gurtov, Melvin and Konrad Kellen, "Vietnam: Lessons and Mislessons,", 1969
          - Huntington, Samuel P., "Military Intervention, Political Involvement, and the Unlessons of Vietnam,", 1968
        - North Vietnamese assessment
    - Voluntary associations
    - Watergate, effects on international relations
    - Yemen, insurgency
    - Yemen, South, insurgency
    - Zanzibar, insurgency
  - DEBRIEFINGS, 1965-1969 (Boxes 96-101)
    Printed copies of debriefings conducted by the U.S. Agency for International Development Asia Training Center, University of Hawaii, Honolulu.
    - AID education advisor, Region II, Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 96)
    - AID educational advisor, Region II, Vietnam, 1966
    - AID officer, Region III, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - AID official, Vietnam, 1966
    - AID provincial representative, Kien Tuong, Vietnam, 1965-1966
    - AID refugee advisor, Quang Tri Province, Vietnam, 1967
    - AID representative, Vietnam and Laos, 1963-1967 (Box 97)
    - AID secretary in Saigon, and IVS teacher in Hue, Vietnam, (Marybeth Clark), 1961-1967
    - AID sociologist, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - Agriculture advisor, Vietnam, 1966-1968
    - American businessman, Saigon, Vietnam, 1962-1968
    - American nurse advisor, Dalat, Tuyen Doc Province, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - American nurse advisor, Nha Trang, Khanh Hoa Province, Vietnam, (Miss Helene Mac Neill), 1965-1967
    - Assistant land reform advisor, Vietnam, 1965-1967
    - Assistant provincial representative, Chau Doc and Gia Dinh Provinces, Vietnam, 1965-1968
    - Assistant provincial representative, Chau Doc Province, Vietnam, 1964-1965
    - CORDS deputy district advisor, Dat Do District, Phuoc Tuy Province, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - CORDS deputy province senior advisor, Thua Thien and An Xuyen Provinces, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - CORDS management consultant (administration), Saigon, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - CORDS psychological operations officer, Region III, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - CORDS representative, Binh Duong Province, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - CORDS sanitarian, Vietnam, 1968-1969
    - District representative, Binh Thuan, Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Box 98)
    - Education advisor, Region II, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - Education advisor, Saigon, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - Education advisor, Vietnam, 1966-1968
    - Forestry advisor (agriculture), Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - Former senior AID official, Saigon, Vietnam, 1957-1967
    - Former senior AID official, Vietnam, (Albert S. Fraleigh), 1962-1967
    - General services officer (administration), Region I, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - Land reform advisor (training), Vung Tau, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - Logistics coordinator, Saigon, Vietnam, 1963-1966
    - Military information specialist, Dinh Tuong Province, Vietnam, 1967-1968
    - Military sub-sector advisor, Ben Cat, Binh Duong Province, Vietnam, 1966-1967
    - New Life Development advisor, Kontum, Vietnam, 1968-1969
    - New Life Development officer, Phong Dinh Province, Vietnam, (Jaime Concepcion), 1967-1968
    - Prison advisor (public safety), Phuoc Tuy, Thua Thien, and Gia Dinh, Vietnam, 1960-1967
    - Province representative, An Giang Province, Vietnam, 1965-1967